James Russell Stirling

94 Redwood Drive, Bradley, Huddersfield, West Yorkshire, HD2 1PW Home- 01484 453 702 Mobile- 07827 013643

Email - jamesstirling01@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a confident and well-rounded IT professional. IT has been a part of my life since I received my first computer and I have mostly tutored myself. Working at Millennium, Emis, Goldfield Computing Limited and Direct Data Systems has helped me develop and gain the necessary experience to further my career. I am a very approachable and professional individual and have always enjoyed being part of a team although; I am equally at ease working on my own. I am a keen learner and I am keen to develop and grow within other companies.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Third Lind Systems Engineer, Direct Data Systems

2013 - Present Day

- Support and maintain internal and in house systems and servers
- First point of action for clients whether that be remotely or onsite.
- Support and maintain 30+ servers & backup systems. Monitoring them all daily and troubleshooting any problems that may occur.
- Assist other team members in technical related matters on customers sites & systems.

Systems Engineer, Goldfield Computing Limited

2007- 2013

- Support and maintain 30 servers. Monitoring them all daily and troubleshooting any problems that may occur.
- First point of action for clients whether that be remotely or onsite.
- Repair customer's hardware as and when needed, which on average is 10 a week.
- I go out on site as and when needed, to install servers (SBS 2011).

Support Consultant, Emis Limited

2006-2007

- Responsible for supporting the users of the LV and PCs System.
- Administrating and supporting the Windows Server NT to Win2003, to secure a good level of performance for the Emis systems
- Communicating with clients advising verbally, computing skills to solve their technical problems within the system.
- Communicating with engineers to help with the ongoing support of the users within the Emis systems.

Technical Support Assistant, Millenium Direct

2002-2006

- Responsible for the company-s information technology.
- Responsible for the day to day running of the department including server and desktop management.
- Responsible for the Purchasing of IT equipment.

Skills

Operating Systems- 98SE, 2000, XP Pro, Vista, Windows 7, Windows Server 2000, Windows Server 2003, Windows Server 2003 R2, Windows Server 2008, Windows Server 2008 R2, Windows Server 2012, Windows 2012 R2, Windows Server 2016, Windows Server 2019 Macintosh-Apple.

Server Software- Active Directory Users & Computers, Exchange 5.5 to Exchange 2019, ISA Server Firewall 2004, HyperV DNS, DHCP, Group Policy, VPN\RAS, IIS6.0 - IIS7 WSUS Server.

Microsoft Business Applications- Microsoft Outlook 97 - 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft Word 97 - 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft Excel 97 - 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft FrontPage 97 - 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft Publisher 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft PowerPoint 97 - 2000 - XP - 2003 - 2007 - 2010, Microsoft Visio 2000 - 2003 - 2007 - 2010.

Programming- Visual Basic - 6.0, Visual Basic Applications, VB Scripting Visual Basic .NET.

Security Products- Mcafee Protection Pilot Mcafee SaaS, Bit Defender Management Server Exchange and File, Sophos Business Edition, Kapersky Business Edition, Bitlocker, Sonicwall.

Backup Solutions- Remote Backup Systems, Vembu - StoreGrid, Backup. Barracuda Online Backup, Backup Software Versions 9.0 -10.0, NT-Backup, Windows Server, Veritas

Third Party Software- Sage Line 50 Versions, ACT By Sage Version 5.5 - 2009, 2010, 2011, Blackberry Systems BIS - BES, Alchemy Telephone System -Manager GFI Anti Spam, GFI Web Monitor.

Technical- In depth technical knowledge of supporting and administrating Windows Server 2000 - 2019 Exchange 5.5 - 2019 MS firewall via ISA 2004, Terminal services.- Network administration also included RAS/VPN, network hubs, routers, antivirus and security etc.

I have excellent experience in the installation, training and support of desktop environments including Windows 98 to Windows 10 and MS Office 2000 - 2019

I am also a skilled programmer in Visual Basic 6.0 Programming skills include VB6 for both internal and external applications & Visual Basic.Net.

Education

Shipley College- NVQ Installing and Supporting IT Systems, Create Software Components using visual basic 6.0 Pass- Distinction, Develop software using visual basic (MC) Pass-Distinction.

Rastrick High School- 2 Merit / 2 Pass GNVQ.

Hobbies/Interests

In my spare time I enjoy socializing. I am a keen mountain biker and own 2 bikes which range from a full suspension and also a hard tail. I enjoy playing squash and I am a member of the squash league at my local sports center.

References

Excellent references are available upon request.